<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>miscellaneous on peregrinator&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/misc.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in miscellaneous on peregrinator&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2012-2023 Brihadeesh S All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 18:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How culture has affected natural selection in man</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/misc/2018/03/how-culture-has-affected-natural-selection-in-man.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 18:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/misc/2018/03/how-culture-has-affected-natural-selection-in-man.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Culture is arguably unique to humans. It possibly arose from the need&#xA;to manage larger groups of people that congregated near agricultural&#xA;fields as Jared Diamond suggests in Guns, Germs and Steel&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; although it may&#xA;have originated in tribal or hunter-gatherer societies. It is strongly&#xA;linked with religion which can viewed as a cement holding together&#xA;larger population masses. Recent developments in its research suggests&#xA;two perspectives of culture: an outcome of natural selection which&#xA;considers humans part of “nature” and culture as a purely human&#xA;construct which arose as a consequence of advanced emotional&#xA;intelligence which natural selection (according to believers of this&#xA;theory) cannot explain. In order to see the effects on natural&#xA;selection, one has to take a neutral stance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability and the Common Man</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/misc/2017/03/sustainability-and-the-common-man.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 10:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/misc/2017/03/sustainability-and-the-common-man.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Policy with respect to sustainability in India has never been top&#xA;priority, until very recently. It has often been fraught with people&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;predispositions that should never have come about in the first&#xA;place. I will be talking about the ways of a singe man I know, let&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;call him Devdas (original name withheld for various reasons) and how&#xA;almost all of his actions were made knowing about the state of&#xA;wildlife in India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
